JOSIAH ENUMAH

23 Dahomey Street, Ogundero B/Stop, Gbagada New Garage, Lagos, Nigeria ♦ +2348084809607 ♦ josiahenumah94@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly meticulous leader and a Software, Systems & Support Engineer with extensive expertise in General Management, M365 Technical Support, Cloud security, Azure, and web application development. Proactive, logical, and analytical thinker, committed to exceeding workplace targets and goals, while empowering teams to achieve peak performance. Diligently advocates for Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), upholding unwavering integrity and a steadfast commitment to excellence.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, HTML & CSS
- React.Js & Meteor.Js
- Semantic & Material UI
- Redux & State Management
- Styled Components, Tailwind & Bootstrap
- Git, Figma & Atlassian Tools
- M365 & Azure Technical Support

- Cloud & Cyber Security
- Software & Hardware Engineering
- General Management
- Product and Project Management
- Facilities Management
- Business Analysis
- Environment, Health & Safety

WORK HISTORY

Tek Experts – Lagos State, Nigeria

M365 Technical Support Engineer, 09/2023 – Present

- Proficiently addressing Microsoft 365 and Azure issues, demonstrating expert troubleshooting & problem-solving skills.
- Consistently exceeding monthly CSAT scores of 4.72+, displaying unwavering commitment to exceptional technical support.
- Perpetually attaining monthly Quality metrics, guaranteeing exceptional service standards and customer satisfaction.
- Sustaining over 50% monthly Survey Response Rate (SRR), showcasing solid customer engagement and feedback collection.

King Cabana Limited – Lagos State, Nigeria

Frontend Developer, 11/2022 - 01/2024

- Enhanced user experience through JavaScript, Redux, and Version Control tools for mobile and desktop platforms.
- Accelerated MVP launch by 25% with React reusable components, garnering positive QA test feedback.
- Implemented seamless frontend-backend integration, ensuring efficient data flow and application performance.

Unfair Advantage – Helsinki, Finland

Front End Engineer, 03/2023 – 06/2023

- Optimised Staff Tribes app with Meteor.js: integrating APIs, Figma screens and boosting the responsiveness by 45%.
- Cooperated with stakeholders to ensure stafftribes.com aligned with project requirements and initial specifications.
- Pioneered "user best-matches feature", coordinated extensive product testing, fixed bugs and upgraded app performance.

Green Facilities Limited – Lagos, Nigeria

Facilities Manager, 10/2022 – 12/2022

- Managed technicians, contractors, and service providers using SERVO CMMS software and Microsoft tools.
- Automated facility management processes at Bridge Clinic, Ikeja GRA, and Historia Mews Estate, Lekki, achieving operational excellence.

Triple E Diagnostics – Delta State, Nigeria

Product Manager, 06/2021 – 08/2022

- Established collaborative partnerships with 19 pharmacies and the University of Delta, Agbor.
- Branded the company, created the business plan, and managed strategic online presence.
- Maximized SEO, elevating website views by 63% and search visibility by 127%, expanding the customer base.

Facility Engineer, 06/2021 – 09/2021

- Oversaw setup, installation, and maintenance of critical equipment at the medical facilities.
- Implemented stringent safety protocols, ensuring zero equipment damage or casualties.
- Provided on-site support for computer systems, printers, and various equipment, yielding smooth operations.

Fenster Academy – Ogun State, Nigeria

IT Engineer & Instructor, 10/2020 - 05/2021

- Facilitated trainings, rendered IT support and displayed team leadership, boosting personnel's resourcefulness by 75%.
- Addressed practical matters on special modules whilst offering expert and reliable solutions, manifesting a 90% success rate.
- Maintained equipment in line with HSE practices, ensuring 100% damage-free operations.

Slot Systems Limited – Lagos State, Nigeria

Computer Engineering Intern, 01/2016 - 06/2016

- Settled 95% of technical impediments for Windows, MAC-OS and LINUX-based devices within service level agreements.
- Worked directly with the CTO to customize computing systems, enhancing client satisfaction and retention by 40%.
- Resolved complex problems within deadlines, obtaining a 98% customer issue resolution rate.25%.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Engineering Physics - Obafemi Awolowo University, 2020

—— CERTIFICATIONS —

- ITIL ® v4 Foundation IT Service Management, QA Ltd
- PRINCE2 Foundation, QA Ltd
- Cybersecurity Fundamentals, Cisco Networking Academy
- Career Essentials in System Administration, Microsoft & LinkedIn
- M365 Commercial Technical Training, Tek Experts, Nigeria
- The Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy
- Product Management Principles: Entrylevel.Net, Australia
- Professional Ethics: Corporate Finance Institute (CFI), Canada
- Associate Project Management Professional (PMP): International Institute of Project and Safety Management, IIPSM Nigeria
- HSE/EIA Professional, IIPSM, Nigeria
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing: Google Digital Skills, Nigeria

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ———

Discover more about my volunteering experiences, awards, and detailed project portfolio by visiting the following platforms:

- LinkedIn Profile: https://linkedin.com/in/josiah-enumah
- GitHub: https://github.com/JosiahENUMAH
- Website Portfolio: https://josiahenumah.netlify.app/